Web Application Developer

Experienced software engineer with focus on Ruby on Rails web application development. Staunch believer in programming best practices, test-driven development, and agile methodology. Able to communicate effectively with clients and colleagues. Passion for writing clear, concise, readable code. Possesses a perpetual desire to teach, learn from, and cooperate with others.

Specialties: Ruby, JavaScript/CoffeeScript, CSS/Sass, HTML5

Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, jQuery
Testing Tools: Test::Unit, MiniTest, RSpec

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite3, MySQL, MongoDB
Platforms: Mac OSX, Linux, FreeBSD, Windows

Other: C#, VB.NET, Java, C/C++, XAML, WPF, WCF

EXPERIENCE

Cetrasoft LLC 2010 - Present

Freelance Web Developer

Worked on a wide variety of web and corporate identity projects. Coordinated concept through implementation, concentrating on backend design, user interface enhancements through AJAX and JavaScript, deployment, and optimizations.

Web Projects Include:

oneworldbuttons.com - Button manufacturer nobleinsights.com - Industry expert recruitment service quoteboardapp.com - Social network site findcarlove.com - Vehicle matching site

Total Computer Software

2008 - 2011

Senior Software Engineer

Architected and implemented an inter-agency data sharing system using C#, the .NET framework, and Windows Communication Foundation with an emphasis on interoperability, distributability, and security.

Designed and implemented a mapping system which integrates with ESRI ArcGIS web services to display maps, locate addresses, and retrieve geo-data.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Guest speaker at the EMEA international public safety conference in Barcelona, Spain for an audience of over eighty people
- ▶ Invited to collaborate with project managers and developers to improve and test software for the .NET 4.0 framework at the Microsoft Technology Centers in San Francisco and New York City

EDUCATION

Williams College, Williamstown, MA 2004 - 2008 BA in Computer Science

Carlos Ramirez III

carlosramireziii@me.com www.carlosramireziii.me www.carlosramireziii.com